{
    "id": "cda9b35405114dffae2a20dcd1aab4ef",
    "title": "Sentence completion worksheet",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "04c7efd5cabc4ec486235f9922939b78",
            "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Think twice before you take a sip …………………. that cola bottle this summer.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "from",
                        "off",
                        "of",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Scientists ..................... that excessive cola consumption can lead to everything from muscle weakness to profound muscle paralysis.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "have warned",
                        "are warning",
                        "has warned"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is …………………cola drinks can cause blood potassium levels to drop to dangerously low levels.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "as",
                        "since",
                        "like",
                        "because"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "A report published in the International Journal of Clinical Practice tells the curious case of an Australian ostrich farmer who ………………… emergency care for lung paralysis after drinking 4-10 liters of cola a day.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "needs",
                        "has needed",
                        "needed",
                        "needing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He made a full recovery and ……………….. to reduce his cola intake.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "advised",
                        "has advised",
                        "was advised"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "id": "c308972c4b5d48eda16f3dafb5c98a7c",
            "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She asked me ………………… I had met her parents before.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "if",
                        "that",
                        "whether if"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The constable asked the man what …………………. there at that time of the night.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "he is doing",
                        "he was doing",
                        "is he doing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He said that he was not feeling well, so I suggested ………………….",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "him seeing a doctor",
                        "that he should see a doctor",
                        "him to see a doctor"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He asked me whether I ………………. him some money.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "could lend",
                        "could lent",
                        "can lend"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We expected that he ..................... surrender without any resistance.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "would",
                        "will",
                        "would have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Astronomers ……………….  to prove that the sun is stationary and that the earth and other planets move around the sun.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "have able",
                        "have been able",
                        "can able"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The forest was the hiding place of outlaws ……………….. were the gossip of the countryside.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "of whose evil deeds",
                        "whose evil deeds",
                        "the evil deeds of whose"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}